blendr.com 2019-06-28

# Blendr's Privacy Policy

## Blendr is powered by Badoo

## Who we are

Badoo is operated by Badoo Trading Limited, a company registered in England at The Broadgate Tower Third Floor, 20 Primrose Street, London, United Kingdom, EC2A 2RS and company number 07540255.

Badoo has designated a Data Protection Officer and they can be reached by emailing DPO@corp.badoo.com or by post at the address above.

## What information does Badoo process?

Badoo is a meeting place for adults, and we provide that service by operating a social network site offering users the opportunity to connect to our global community of users. By joining Badoo, you enter a legal agreement with us and we process your data in order to provide your service under the terms of that agreement. You can only become a member of Badoo or use its features if you’re aged 18 or over or the age of majority in the country in which you reside if that happens to be greater than 18.

To join the Badoo network you will have to complete our online registration form, where we may ask you to provide us with information about you such as your name, your email address, your gender, your date of birth, your location details. You also have the opportunity to provide other details about yourself, but these are optional. Because you control your user profile, these details are available to you at any time by accessing your “Profile” page, which gives you the chance to correct or update (other than your email address and gender) your information at any time by just logging in to Badoo. You can contact Badoo’s Customer Support Team at our [Feedback Page](http://badoo.com/feedback) to change the gender on your profile and/or email address.

Please be careful about posting sensitive details about yourself on your Profile such as your religious denomination and health details. While you may voluntarily provide this information to us when you create your Profile, including your sexual preferences and ethnic background, there is no requirement to do so. Please remember that photographs or any video clips that you post on Badoo may reveal these kinds of sensitive personal data. Where you do upload and choose to tell us sensitive data about yourself, you are explicitly consenting to our processing your information and making this public to other users.

For safety and security and to ensure you have the best possible user experience, we require users to verify their accounts and might ask for your phone number. We want to make sure you are not a robot! And we also want to avoid fake Badoo accounts being created which can be used for malicious activities and cyber crime – they threaten the Badoo network and spoil things for everyone. We use a third party provider for account verification who will keep your phone number for up to 90 days for fraud identification purposes across a range of online platforms and services like Badoo’s. We collect and use your phone number on the basis of our legitimate interests identified above and for the prevention of fraud.

To prevent abuse of the app/site, Badoo uses automated decisions to block accounts as part of its anti-spam procedures. In order to do this, our systems check accounts and messages for content that indicates breaches of our Terms and Conditions of Use. If an account or message meets certain criteria that demonstrate that the Terms and Conditions of Use are likely to have been breached, the relevant account will automatically be blocked. All users of accounts that have been blocked will be notified that their account has been blocked and affected users can contact Badoo to contest the decision.

If you decide to purchase any of our premium services, we will process your payment information and retain this securely for the prevention of fraud and for audit/tax purposes. Under data protection law, it is necessary for us to collect and process this payment data to enable us to perform our contract with you and our ongoing retention of this data is justified by our legitimate interests set out above.

To enable Badoo to provide a free non-premium service, we process some limited data (demographics and location) to drive targeted advertising in our legitimate interest including sharing such data with advertising networks. We may also receive data indirectly from such advertising networks. You can stop this within Settings but you will still see adverts, though they will be less relevant to you. Through your device’s security settings you also have the option to prevent or limit device identifiers being shared with third party advertisers and what use is made of the device identifiers. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please visit [this page](http://networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

Finally, we want to keep in touch with you to make sure you know about the great promotions and offers we have available. If you’ve told us it’s OK, we will use your email address and phone number to send you information on these. You can withdraw this consent at any time via Settings in the app or website.

## What does Badoo collect about me if I use the mobile App?

Badoo offers you the opportunity to stay in touch with the friends and contacts you’ve made no matter where you are. You can do this by using your mobile phone or by downloading an application to your desktop that allows you to share your location with other users.

When you use your mobile or the desktop application, we will collect information about WiFi access points as well as other location information about your longitude and latitude. That information helps us identify your physical location so that it can be displayed and shared with other members choosing to view “nearby” posts.

If you have enabled location services, but wish to turn it off, you can do so by the following methods:

  1. iPhone app — settings, privacy, location services, Badoo
  2. Android — settings, location, Badoo, permissions, location

We, or our third-party advertising partners, may also collect and use your device identifier to serve relevant ads to you through the App. You can opt out of targeted advertising by (i) becoming a payer and/ or (ii) opting not to share data with any partner platforms but still to receive advertisements.

If you log in to or access Badoo through your Facebook profile, we may collect data including your email address, name and profile picture, date of birth, a list of your friends who also use the app, pages you have liked, location and photos in order to create and update your Badoo profile. You may also appear on your friends’ Facebook apps as a Badoo user.

## What is the legal basis that allows Badoo to use my data?

We are only permitted to use your data when we have a lawful basis to do so. The table below provides an overview of the legal bases that Badoo relies on to use your data. Where the legal basis is consent, you can withdraw consent at any time. Where the legal basis is legitimate interests, you have a right to object to our use of your data. We explain in the relevant sections in this privacy notice how you can withdraw consent or opt-out of certain data uses (where applicable).

Purpose for which data is used | Data | Legal basis  
---|---|---  
To provide you with the Badoo social networking service | Name, email address, date of birth, location | Contractual necessity  
To facilitate networking opportunities on the Badoo site | Optional information that you choose to provide in your profile, which may include information about your sexual preferences, religion, ethnic background, photos etc. | Consent  
To verify your identity and prevent fraud and to ensure the safety and security of users | Phone number | Legitimate interests – it is in our legitimate interests to ensure that accounts are not set up fraudulently and to safeguard users of the site  
To take payment for premium services | Payment card details | Contractual necessity and legitimate interests – we have a legitimate interest in receiving payment for our premium services  
To serve targeted advertisements to users of the site | Demographic and location information | Legitimate interests – it is in our legitimate interests to target advertisements so that users see relevant advertisements and to allow us to generate income from advertising revenue  
To send you marketing information about our offers and services | Email address and cell phone number | Legitimate interests – it is in our legitimate interests to promote our products and services  
To enable users to create their Badoo profile and log in to the app via Facebook | Data from Facebook, including email address, name and profile picture, date of birth, friends who use the app, pages liked, location and photos | Legitimate interests – it is in our legitimate interests to promote our products and services  
To show “nearby” location information to you and other users of the site | Wifi access points and location data when you use the mobile app | Consent  
To serve advertisements through the Badoo mobile app | Device ID | Legitimate interests – it is in our legitimate interests and the interests of third party advertisers to deliver advertisements to you to promote their products  
To provide the lookalikes function | Photos and faceprint | Legitimate interests – it is in our legitimate interests to provide this functionality  
To carry out analysis to help us improve the app | Log and usage data, including IP address, browser type, referring domain, pages accessed, mobile carrier and search terms | Legitimate interests – it is in our interests to analyze the way in which users are accessing and using our services so that we can further develop the app and improve the service  
To respond to correspondence and queries that you submit to us | Email address and IP address | Legitimate interests – it is in our legitimate interests to respond to your queries to ensure that we provide a good service to users and troubleshoot problems  
To block accounts as part of our anti-spam procedures | Email address, phone number, IP address and IP session information, social network ID, username, faceprint, user agent string | Legitimate interests – it is in our legitimate interests to prevent unauthorized behavior and to maintain the safety and security of our services  
  
## How long will Badoo keep my data?

We keep your personal information only as long as we need it for legitimate business purposes (as set out above) and as permitted by applicable law.

In practice, we delete or anonymize your information upon deletion of your account (following the safety retention window), unless:

  1. we must keep it to comply with applicable law (for instance, some “traffic data” is kept for one year to comply with statutory data retention obligations);
  2. we must keep it to evidence our compliance with applicable law (for instance, records of consents to our Terms, Privacy Policy and other similar consents are kept for five years);
  3. there is an outstanding issue, claim or dispute requiring us to keep the relevant information until it is resolved; or
  4. the information must be kept for our legitimate business interests, such as fraud prevention and enhancing users' safety and security. For example, information may need to be kept to prevent a user who was banned for unsafe behavior or security incidents from opening a new account.

## What information does Badoo collect about me if I’m under 18?

Badoo does not knowingly collect any information about or market to children, minors or anyone under the age of majority. If we become aware that a child, minor or anyone under the age of 18 has registered with us and provided us with personal data, we will take steps to terminate that person’s registration and delete their Profile information from Badoo. If we do delete a Profile because you violated our no children rules, we may retain your email and IP address to ensure that you do not try to get around our rules by creating a new Profile.

## What information does Badoo collect about my friends and contacts?

You can choose to invite your friends to join Badoo to make sure that they also get the benefits of meeting new people. To make it easier to search and find friends and acquaintances on Badoo, users may search for other members by email address. If you want to invite your friends and contacts to Badoo, we will send an email invitation from Badoo in your name or you can send an SMS (if you use our Android or iPhone App) to your friends and contacts encouraging them to sign up to Badoo. If any of the individuals you have invited do not register within a few days, Badoo may occasionally send reminder emails on your behalf to those individuals. You can choose to invite all your friends or only a select few by simply unticking the names of those friends you do not wish to invite, but please remember you must not invite any children to join. You are responsible for ensuring that your friend has agreed to receiving a Badoo invite.

When you import your contacts, we store their name and email address or their cell phone number so that we can automatically connect you and your friend. Badoo does not sell these email addresses or cell phone numbers or use them to send any other communication besides email invitations. The friend may contact Badoo to request the removal of their information from our database by visiting our [Feedback Page](http://badoo.com/feedback). Any such request will only apply to addresses or cell phone numbers we have at the time of the request and not to any addresses or cell phone numbers that the member/user provides to us later.

## Who does Badoo share information with?

We may share aggregated information with such parties as Foursquare that includes your personal data (but which doesn’t identify you directly), together with other information including log data with third parties for industry analysis and demographic profiling and to deliver targeted advertising about other products and services.

We share your data with the following categories of third-parties:

  1. Information technology companies (hardware and software) which provide services to support our products
  2. Fraud prevention and anti-spam providers to protect the service from criminal activity
  3. Moderators to monitor activity on the site/apps and approve content
  4. Advertising partners, market places and providers of targeted advertising, including, but not limited to, MoPub Inc. (you can view MoPub’s privacy policy at https://www.mopub.com/legal/privacy/ and its partner list at https://www.mopub.com/legal/partners/) and Unity Technologies SF (you can view Unity’s privacy policy at https://unity3d.com/legal/privacy-policy).
  5. Law enforcement agencies, where we are required to by law or to protect the vital interests of a person
  6. Payment processing and telecommunications companies to facilitate payments for our premium services

We ensure these parties must adhere to strict data protection and confidentiality provisions that are consistent with this Policy. Measures are taken to ensure that the data shared is non-attributable to the greatest extent possible.

In the event that Badoo or any of its affiliates undergoes a business transition or change of ownership, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, re-organization, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, or in the event of insolvency or administration, we may be required to disclose your personal data.

## How does lookalikes work?

Lookalikes is one feature of the site which is primarily designed to allow you to find people who look similar to celebrities, friends or even you! The feature will return photos of people who look like the person you searched for and who are existing members of Badoo. After using the feature you will be invited to create a Badoo account so that you can contact these “lookalikes” and possibly meet (only if they agree of course!).

We respect other people’s rights, and you should too. We recognize that as well as uploading a photo of yourself to find your lookalike, you may wish to upload a photo of someone else to find their lookalikes. If you do, then you should get their permission before you upload their photo. You are not permitted to upload photos of children.

Any photos that are uploaded for use in lookalikes will be stored on our servers until your account is deleted. If you wish for the photo to be deleted before then (e.g. you have been contacted by the person in the photo you uploaded seeking immediate removal of the photo), you may contact us via email at [lookalike@badoo.com](mailto:lookalike@badoo.com) to make your request. Please be aware that it may take up to 72 hours for us to process your request.

## Your rights

Under UK and EU law, you have the right to lodge a complaint with data protection regulators. Badoo has its main office in the UK and the Information Commissioners’ Office (ICO) is our lead regulator. You can find out how to raise a concern with the ICO by visiting their website at www.ico.org.uk. If you’re within the EU, you may also get in touch with your local Data Protection Regulator who may liaise with the ICO on your behalf.

You have a number of rights under European Data Protection law if you are an EU citizen.

  1. Right to be informed: what personal data an organization is processing and why (this notice).
  2. Right of access: you can request a copy of your data.
  3. Right of rectification: if the data held is inaccurate, you have the right to have it corrected.
  4. Right to erasure: you have the right to have your data deleted in certain circumstances.
  5. Right to restrict processing: in limited circumstances, you have the right to request that processing is stopped but the data retained.
  6. Right to data portability: you can request a copy of your data in a machine-readable form that can be transferred to another provider.
  7. Right to object: in certain circumstances (including where data is processed on the basis of legitimate interests or for the purposes of marketing) you may object to that processing.
  8. Rights related to automated decision making including profiling: there are several rights in this area where processing carried out on a solely automated basis results in a decision which has legal or significant effects for the individual. In these circumstances your rights include the right to ensure that there is human intervention in the decision-making process.

If you want to exercise any of your rights listed above please visit our Feedback Page or email us at DPO@corp.badoo.com. You can also contact us by post at The Broadgate Tower, Third Floor, 20 Primrose Street, London, United Kingdom, EC2A 2RS.

## How does Badoo protect my personal data?

Badoo has implemented appropriate security measures to protect and prevent the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control, including your personal data. Our technical experts at Badoo work hard to ensure your secure use of our site.

While we take reasonable precautions against possible security breaches of our website, member database and records, no website or internet transmission is completely secure and we cannot guarantee that unauthorized access, hacking, data loss, or other breaches will never occur. We urge you to take steps to keep your personal data safe (including your password) and to log out of your account after use. If you lose your password or give it out, or another service provider that you use suffers a data breach and you have used the same credentials with that service provider as you have with Badoo, your personal data may be compromised. If that happens, please report it to Support via our Feedback page.

## Where is my personal data kept?

We want you to be able to access Badoo wherever you happen to be in the world. To enable us to provide that service, we operate a global network of servers including in the US, Hong Kong, Czech Republic and Russia. The hardware is located in third-party data centres but is owned by Badoo. Data collected by advertising partners may also be held outside the European Economic Area. We ensure that the data is adequately protected by ensuring that valid, legal mechanisms are in place such as: EU approved model clauses (which can be found [here](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en)), US privacy shield certification (more information can be found [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome)); and implementing robust contractual standards. If you want more information relating to the nature of the safeguards we have in place please email DPO@corp.badoo.com.

## Does Badoo collect any other personal data about me?

If you contact our Customer Support team via our [Feedback page](https://blendr.com/feedback/), we will receive your email address, and may track your IP address as well as the information you send to us to help resolve your query. We will keep records of our communications with you, including any complaints that we receive from you about other users (and from other users about you) for 6 years after deletion of your account.

## Does Badoo use my personal data for any other purpose?

We may use material that you post on the open access areas of Badoo in advertising and promotional materials on our partner sites and partner products. We believe these uses are in line with our legitimate interests in enabling us to improve our site and better tailor your online experience to meet your needs. If we intend to do this, we will contact you for your prior approval.

From time to time we may run surveys for research purposes and we may contact you to find out if you would like to take part. Such surveys are optional and more information will be provided at the point of contact. If you do not wish to be contacted to take part in a survey, please contact our Customer Support Team at our [Feedback Page](http://badoo.com/feedback).

We use your personal data to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems and enforce our [Terms and Conditions of Use](https://blendr.com/terms/).

### What are ‘cookies’ and what ‘cookies’ does Badoo use?

We collect information by placing cookies on your computer or mobile device. A cookie is a piece of text stored on your computer or mobile device by your web browser. They are basically a tool that stores information about website visits, recognizes you and your preferences each time you visit Badoo, and ensures site functionality and enables us to provide the services our members request.

When you visit the publicly available sections of Badoo, a session ID cookie is placed on your computer that only lasts while you’re visiting. We also place persistent cookies (also known as local storage devices) on members’ computers, so that Badoo remembers them and makes their login experience faster and easier. We may use persistent tracking cookies on your mobile device, mainly for security protection purposes, such as to prevent phishers, scammers, unauthorized login attempts, and to help you access your hacked account. We do not use any information whilst you are logged off.

You may set your browser and your mobile settings to block cookies and local storage devices, but if you do so, you may not be able to access the features that Badoo offers.

Badoo’s use of cookies and local storage devices basically falls into the following categories:

  * those that are strictly necessary to deliver the services and products you have requested, such as, for example purchasing Badoo Premium;
  * cookies related to the performance of Badoo’s site, such as analytics that help us determine how our site is performing and ensure a smooth and trouble-free experience for our members and visitors;
  * cookies related to the functionality of Badoo’s site, such as remembering your preferences at login or your preferred language or allowing you to chat, add photos and instant message Badoo members;
  * third party cookies which link to other social networks and which you request via social plugins; and
  * cookies used to improve and target advertising to you based on what’s relevant to you, to improve reporting on any advertising campaign and to avoid showing you ads you have already seen.

Badoo uses cookies and local storage devices so that we know who you are, what interests you and so that you can do the things online that you want to do, like chat with new people, share your content and buy Badoo Premium knowing that your data will be secure. Below is a table to explain Badoo’s cookie functions and why they’re used.

Cookie Functions | Cookie Purposes  
---|---  
Analytics and research | Badoo uses Google Analytics to collect information about how visitors use the Badoo site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. For more information about Google’s privacy policy, please visit <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/>  
Authentication | These cookies help us to identify our members so that when you’re logged in, you can enjoy Badoo’s offerings, experiences and various features, such as uploading photographs, chatting and can localize your experience, such as when you’ve requested to view Badoo’s site in your local language or when you’ve asked Badoo to ‘remember me’. These cookies also help to remember who invited you to join Badoo.  
Security and site integrity | 

We use cookies and other devices, such as CAPTCHAs, to help keep Badoo and our members safe and secure. These cookies do things like protect Badoo users from spam and fraud, by ensuring the safety of your personal data when you shop on Badoo for things like Badoo Premium.

We may use persistent cookies, which will help us to ensure we have identified the same device is logging in to the correct account. These types of cookies also help with our anti-spam measures and may help us to prevent phishers, scammers, unauthorized login attempts to your account and accessing any hacked accounts.  
  
Site features and services | These cookies and local storage devices provide the functionality that our Badoo members enjoy, such as uploading photographs, chats, instant messaging, your account settings and your request to have Badoo as your homepage or your search preference. We also use cookies to help provide experiences, such as links to other social media sites, social plugins and video content, including making it easier for you to share content between Badoo with your other favorite social networks. 

In some cases, the site feature you choose may allow a third party to place cookies or local storage devices on your computer. The third party who places cookies on your device is responsible for how they process their data and Badoo recommends that you read their privacy policies. Third parties who place cookies on your device when you use Badoo include, and we have included a link to their privacy policies:

  * Twitter, <https://twitter.com/privacy>
  * Facebook, <https://en-gb.facebook.com/policy.php>
  * YouTube, <http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/policies/privacy/>
  * AddThis, <http://www.addthis.com/privacy>

Performance | We need to use certain cookies and local storage devices to ensure our members have the best possible experience, such as assisting with your navigation of our site, ensuring pages load up quickly and respond faster to your requests for Badoo services  
Targeted advertising | We sometimes conduct advertising campaigns using DoubleClick, a Google company, who will also place cookies. To find out about DoubleClick cookies and how to control those cookies, go to: <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>.  
  
Our use of cookies and local share devices, including the specific cookie names, may change over time, but will generally fall into the above categories. We will notify you of any important changes to our use of cookies and local storage devices If you would like to know more about cookies, including flash cookies/local storage devices, the following websites provide useful information:

  * <http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html>

This Privacy Policy was last updated on 14 May 2019.
